你们好
Hey there, Polycasters.
我是 Rob
Rob here.
在上一集的 Polycast 中
In the last episode of "Polycast"
我向你演示了如何在 HTML 中绑定子属性
I showed you how to bind to sub properties in your markup.
但我彻底忘记告诉你如何
But I totally forgot to show you how
在 JavaScript 中做这些绑定
to bind to those same changes in your JavaScript.
这是 Polymer 一个很酷的特性  叫做 observer
It's actually a really cool feature of Polymer called observers.
让我们看看
So let's check those out.
一个声明的属性可以拥有一个 observer 方法
A declared properties can have an observer
在每次属性更改时运行
method that runs every time that property changes.
我已经在几集之前就向你演示过了
And I showed how that worked in a few episodes prior.
所以如果你还没有看过的话  你可以输入
So if you haven't seen that, you can go follow this link
下面的链接来查看
right here to check that out.
但我们现在有的基本上就是这个
But basically, what I've got right here
x-unicorn 元素有一个叫 sparkles 的属性
is this x-unicorn element has a property called sparkles
和一个叫 sparklesChanged 的 observer 函数
and an observer that I've defined
也就是这个函数
called sparkles change, which is this function down here that
每次 sparkles 更新时就会运行
will run any time sparkles is updated.
这就是第一种 observer 函数
So that's the first kind of observer function.
也是大多数开发者熟悉的一种
And it's one that a lot of developers are familiar with.
但还有一种很酷的方式我们还没有讨论到
But one that we haven't talked about yet,
是使用 observer 数组的能力
which is really cool, is the ability to use this observer's array.
就像之前提到的 observer 方法
So, like the previously mentioned observer method,
我们可以用这个数组来指定一个属性变化时
we can use this array to specify a handler that should
运行的 handler
run when a property changes.
你可以在数组中增加一个
And you do this by adding a method name, which is a string,
字符串类型的方法名
to the array.
在括号中写下你想要观察的属性
And in parentheses, you put the property that you want to observe.
在这个例子中  我有一个 zombie-manager 元素
So in this case, I have a zombie manager element.
我的属性都是 zombie 对象
And my properties are the zombies object.
我的 observer 数组中有一个 observer
My observers array has one observer in it, which
也就是 zombiesChanged 函数
is the zombies change function.
它监听着 zombies 属性
And it's looking at the zombies property.
每当对象更新时
And anytime that object is updated,
它会运行这里的 handler
it's going to run this handler right here
获取新的 zombies 对象
and get the new zombies object.
但我们可以用 observer 数组做更多的事情
But there's a lot more that we can do with the observers array.
比如说  我们可以用它来观察对象的子属性
For instance, we can use it to observe element sub properties.
如果我想监视 zombies.hunger
So if I want to look at zombies.hunger,
我可以这样做
then I have it do that instead.
get 到的新值传递给 hungerChanged 函数
And that new value with get passed to this hungerChanged function.
真正酷的是
What's really cool is, we can actually
我们可以同时观察很多属性
observe multiple properties at the same time.
这点很赞  因为如果你有一个方法
And what's great about that is, if you have a method
只想在那些属性值存在时运行
that you want to run only when those properties have a value,
这是一个好方法
this is a good approach to use because that method right
因为任何一个属性是 undefined  null  或者类似的值
there's not going to execute if any of these properties
这里的方法不会运行
is undefined, or null, or anything like that.
如果你有你有异步属性
So if you have asynchronous properties that
需要一点时间初始化什么的
take a little while to initialization or something
与其写一些复杂的逻辑
like that, rather than writing some of the complex logic
来跟踪它们
to keep track of all of them, you
不如直接用一个 observer 来监视多个属性
can just use an observer to watch multiple properties.
当它们最后获取到值时  触发某个函数
And when they all finally have a value, just kick off some function.
这是非常非常实用的技巧
It's a really, really handy trick.
让我写一个简单的例子来演示 observer 是如何工作的吧
Let me do a quick example to demonstrate how observers work.
我在这里创建了一些元素
I've got this element that I've created here.
我已经简化了很多东西
And I've really simplified it down,
你看到的只是定义中重要的部分
so you're only seeing the important parts of the definition.
在上面有一个 image 标签
Up here, at the top, I've got an image tag, which would be,
我们假设它在模板之中
presumably, inside of my template.
我们还有一个 Blurb 的绑定
And then I've got this binding for Blurb right here.
值从 observer 函数中来
And that value is going to come from my observer function.
在元素定义中  我有这个 bio 属性
So in my elements definition, I have this bio property.
这是一个对象  默认为这个人
And that's an object, which defaults to this guy right down here.
这是一个带有 maker 属性的对象
So it's an object with a maker property, which, right now, is
现在被设为 Dr. Frankenstein
set to Dr. Frankenstein.
当它更改时  我们运行 makerChanged
Any time this thing changes, we're going to run maker change.
我们要观察 bio.maker
We're going to observe bio.maker.
然后将 this.blurb 设为新值
And then we'll set this .blurb equal to that new value.
这将会更新上面的绑定
And that is going to go and update our binding right up there.
让我们实践一下
So let's do that in practice.
在开发者工具中  我的元素
Over here in the dev tools, I've got my element rendering
已经渲染出来了
right here.
我已经在 elements 面板中选中了它
I've already got it selected in the elements panel.
我可以用 $0 这个小技巧来指向它
So I can use my $0 trick to refer to it.
我只需要输入 $0.set ('bio.maker','Rob')
And I'll just say $0.set bio.maker to Rob.
更新会表示在视图中
And that's going to update, visually, right there.
现在  如果你对 set 方法不熟悉
Now, if you aren't familiar with the set method,
你可以回去看上一集
you can check out our previous episode, which
其中讲到了使用 set 和 notifyPath
talked about using set and notify path in order
来更新元素的子属性以及绑定这些更新
to update elements sub properties and have those update bindings.
这有点像使用 observer 的实用用法
But this is kind of like a useful way of working with observers.
但事实上 observer 还有一个
But there's actually one last trick that observers
独门秘籍
have up their sleeve.
如果说我们不光要观察 maker 的变化
Let's say instead of just observing maker,
这个对象有差不多 100 个子属性
let's say that, maybe, this object had like 100 sub properties.
我想要观察其中某个属性是否变化了
And I wanted to observe if any of them changed.
如果把所有属性都放进一个臃肿的 observer 函数
It would be really annoying to have to put all of those
将会是非常烦人的
into this one huge observer function.
所以 observer 数组最后一个独门秘籍
And so the last trick up the sleeve of the observer array
便是能够使用通配符
is its ability to look at wild cards.
这里我稍微修改了一些代码
So here I've changed the code a little bit.
现在  我们观察 bio.*  而不是 bio.maker
And now, instead of looking at bio.maker, I'm looking at bio.star.
每个子属性都被监听了
And what that's going to do is observe any sub property.
如果它们是对象
And if these were if these were objects,
它们会有更多子属性
and they had more sub properties,
bio 对象中所有东西都会被观察
they would just observe all that stuff inside of these bio objects.
这是一个非常强大的技术
It's a really powerful technique.
Polymer 不只传递值
And instead of passing just a value, what Polymer
而是传递 handler 函数
is going to pass to our handler function
这被称为变化记录
is going to be what is referred to as a change record.
这是一种特殊的 Polymer 对象
And a change record is sort of like a special Polymer object.
它有三个属性
And it has three properties.
有一个路径
It has a path.
指向变化路径的字符串
And that is a string which refers to the path that changed.
如果我们更改 bio.maker  路径字符串就是 bio.maker
So if we change bio.maker, this path string would be bio.maker.
它有一个值属性  也就是被更新的那个值
It has a value property, which is the actual value that was updated.
最后  它有一个基属性
And then, finally, it has a base property.
基属性指向通配符之前的
And the base property refers to the object
对象
that precedes the wild card.
如果我们要观察 bio.foo.bar.*
So if we were looking at bio.foo.bar.star,
那么基属性就是 bio.foo.bar
then the base property would be bio.foo.bar.
知道了吧
OK?
这里的 bioChanged 函数中
So what I'm doing here is, in my bioChanged function,
我接受变化记录
I'm taking the change record.
观察路径
And I'm looking at the path.
如果是 bio.maker  就做一件事
And if it's bio.maker, I'm doing one thing.
更新这个绑定
I'm updating this binding.
如果是 bio.name  更新另一个绑定
If it's bio.name, I'm updating a different binding, this critter
critter 这个绑定  来更新这里的 span
binding, which is going to update the span right here.
让我们看一眼我们的开发者工具
OK, so over in our dev tools, let's give it a shot.
$0.set ('bio.name','Frank')
So $0 set bio.name.
And we'll set that to Frank.
第一个 span 被更新了
See, that updates our first span.
接下来让我们更新另一个地方
And now, let's update the other thing.
我们将 bio.maker 设为 Rob
We'll set bio.maker to Rob.
和 voila  更新我们另一个绑定
And voila, that updates our other binding.
通过 observer 和变化记录
So with observers and change records,
我们有了在应用中处理新数据的超赞工具
we now have awesome tools for dealing with new data in our app.
我们事实上终于可以开始
And we're actually finally ready to start talking
讨论数组绑定了
about binding to arrays.
我会在下一集中讲这个内容
But I'll save that for the very next episode.
如果你喜欢这集
Now, if you've enjoyed this episode,
请点击下方的订阅按钮
consider clicking the Subscribe button.
如果你对我们有什么疑问
And if you have questions for us,
你可以在你的社交网络上用 #askpolymer 联系我们
you can ping us on a social network of your choosing at #askpolymer.
同样地  感谢观看
As always, thank you so much for watching.
下期再见
And I'll see you next time.
[MUSIC PLAYING]